what's up guys adrian here welcome to my
channel on passive income investing
so a couple of weeks ago i released a
video about how to invest in the big six
canadian banks
so when it comes to financial stocks or
the financial sector as a whole
many people automatically think of banks
so there is a segment however of the
financial sector
that doesn't get the same amount of
attention and notoriety as the banks
these companies usually fly under the
radar so yes i'm talking about life
insurance companies or simply
life calls so the reality is that these
companies are old they're big
and they're lucrative just like the big
banks in addition they tend to be fairly
stable because much of their revenue
comes from insurance premiums
which are long-term and stable contracts
when it comes to canada there are three
big players that dominate the entire
industry
if you're canadian i'm sure you heard
about them number one is
manulife number two is sun life and
number three
is great west life co which recently
consolidated their brands under one name
canada life great west life by the way
is owned primarily by the power
corporation of canada a huge
canadian asset management company which
also owns
investors group and wealth simple so
what about the us well
some big players include metlife which
has that iconic new york city building
you've probably seen in a bunch of
movies
as well as some names like lincoln
national and prudential financial
a couple of others as well right so how
do these companies make so much money
well it's no surprise that life
insurance products are their bread and
butter
but don't think that's their only source
of revenue i did some research on this
and these are some of the insurance
products these companies offer you have
life insurance of course then there's
health insurance travel insurance but
they also have things like critical
illness insurance long-term care
insurance
disability insurance mortgage protection
business owner insurance and i'm sure
there's others that i missed
also don't think that these companies
only offer insurance
products they also manage group and
retirement benefits for other
corporations
for example i work at air canada and
manulife
handles our retirement benefits which
means you're obligated to buy into
manulife owned mutual funds so in
addition to those
insurance products they also offer
investment services to individuals and
businesses
which means they're basically also asset
and wealth management companies in
addition
selling insurance isn't restricted only
to north america
manulife and sunlight for example have
growing revenues from asian markets
so i think you get my point by now these
are not mom-and-pop
companies we're talking about here if
you actually look at how long
they've been in business you realize
that they can be just as old as banks
manulife for example 1887 sun life 1865
great west life 1847 met life
1868 etc etc so they've been in the game
a really
long time they know exactly how to price
their insurance policies because of all
the research and data
they've accumulated over the years which
simply isn't which simply means they
will always be
profitable think of them a bit like a
casino yes there will always be a lucky
one-time winner but all that money
people lose will always
balance out the rare winners hence the
famous
expression the house always wins so i
don't want to ramble on too much on how
these companies
make money but i do want to make one
last point
these companies need to have a lot of
cash on hand to pay out
insurance policies right well what do
you think they do with all that cash on
hand
leave it in the bank making point one
percent interest
i don't think so they invested to make
even more money
with all the data scientists and
financial experts they have on their
staff
they know exactly what they're doing in
terms of investing
some other investing profits do go to
lowering uh premiums or giving out some
small dividends to life insurance
policyholders but rest assured
a lot of it just goes to the bottom line
so what kind of dividends do these
companies
offer us passive income investors well
let's check out the current
dividend yields and the five year
dividend history of manulife and sun
life
just so you could see or get a quick
idea of what kind of dividends you'll be
getting and if it's a good investment or
not
all right so looking at manual life the
biggest player in canada right now the
stock price is at 19
and as you can see from the 52-week
range of 12.58
to 27.78 there's still a lot of catching
up to do that's why
i think these stocks are very uh
discounted right now
if we look at manual life's a dividend
um
yield right now it's 5.89 so really
really good
and even more impressive is the dividend
history so if we look at the five-year
history
you could see in mid-2015 the annual
dividend was
68 cents per share and throughout the
years as you could see here
as we go down it just keeps getting
increased and increased and right now
it's at
a dollar and 12 cents so really nice
increases here for manulife
if we look at sun life it's a bit of the
same story
the stock price right now is 53 26 if we
look at the
52-week range 35 to 66 you could see
that there is
still room for improvement that's why i
think uh sun life is also very
discounted right now
the dividend yield is a bit lower at
4.13
but if we look at the dividend history
it's just as impressive as manulife so
if you go here back to 2015
at a dollar and 52 cents per share
throughout the years just like manulife
they keep increasing it over and over
and right now it's at
two dollars and twenty cents so really
significant uh
dividend increases uh for both companies
in the last five years
so the average dividend yield right now
if you invested let's say in the big
three canadian life goals uh evenly
is a little under six percent not bad
um considering that they consistently
increase their dividends like we just
saw
and also know that all three companies
are discounted right
right now as they have not really fully
recovered from the cove with market
crash making their dividend yields
a lot higher than normal so yes
investing in the stocks individually
just like investing in the stocks
of individual big banks can be a good
choice for the long term
but is there a more efficient way to
invest in these life goals
is there a way to lower your risk and
diversify better
by getting a piece of not only the
canadian ones but the us
giants as well is there a way to invest
without having to pick and choose
individual stocks that can be long
tedious and stressful especially for
amateur investors or investors who
simply don't have the time or simply
don't care lastly and more importantly
is there a way to get
more income than owning the stocks
individually
so the answer is yes to all of those
questions and once again
an etf is the answer so after looking
around
i found an amazing etf from ci first
asset that not only includes the top
life insurance companies in
canada but also in the us and it's
right now it's giving an 11 dividend
so don't believe me let's go check it
out so this is the etf guys
it's the ci first asset us and canada
life co
income etf the stock symbol on the tsx
is
fli so as you can see here in the
description
um it invests in the 10 largest u.s
and canadian life insurance companies by
market cap so you're getting the 10
biggest in north america if we quickly
look at the holdings
you have the 10 companies here so from
canada of course you have the big three
you have sun life
great west life and a manual life and
the others so the other seven
are from the us so of course you have
met life here and
the other big players uh like prudential
and
lincoln so really the best of the best
or the biggest
when it comes to life insurance
companies here now for the best part the
dividends or the distribution so if you
look at the distributions here
you could see that the 12-month trailing
distribution yield which simply means
the average distribution yield for the
last year
is a whopping 11.28 right now
so that's really really great it will
beat
uh owning the individual stocks easily
so we have the breakdown here this etf
was created at the end of 2013
um so if we look at the dividends per
year you could see that
uh they do vary keep in mind that this
etf or actually all et
covered call etfs from ci first asset
number one they give their dividends
quarterly
so every three months and uh they can
vary but if we look at the
from 2016 you could see 70 cents 67
cents 72
70 they're fairly fairly stable where
there was a big jump it was actually in
2020 so usually let's just look at 2019
for example you could see the dividends
here the breakdown
so it's about you have a 19 cents here
15 cents 16 cents
18 cents so on average it's 70 cents
but in 2020 you could see here the first
uh
the the first dividend at the end of
march was 18 cents so it looks pretty
normal
but there was a huge jump in the latest
dividend
it was 33 cents so this actually makes
sense
this is because of the covered calls
this is the power of the covered call so
what happens is that when there's a lot
of volatility in the stock market
the price for uh options goes up which
means that if you have a covered call
etf
where a lot of the revenue comes from
selling uh
covered calls uh you actually make more
money and that's why
you could see here that there was a nice
jump in a dividend
for the quarter so uh 11 yes it will
vary
it might not always be 11 it could be
more it could be less but rest assured
it's gonna be much higher than owning
the stocks individually
so a really really good no-nonsense
stock here you have one stock you have
all the companies all the top life
insurance companies with only one stock
so really really simple and
efficient way here of owning life
insurance companies and getting a lot of
income
in the process so that's it guys the fli
etf is in my opinion the best way to
invest in the top
life insurance companies uh in north
america
they don't get the attention they
deserve in my opinion
for such old and lucrative financial
institutions would that really have a
foolproof business model really a
no-brainer
investment if you ask me also add the
massive dividends you're getting from
the dividends of the stocks and the
covered call premiums
and you got yourself a great income
investment uh giving you cash
every three months or every quarter for
the rest of your life
so thanks for watching guys i really
appreciate it if you learned something
hit the like button and make sure you're
subscribed so you don't miss out on my
future content so take care guys see you
next time